Gihan Kulasena, CAPM

North York, Toronto, ON +1 647-562-9409 gihan.kulasena@hotmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/gihank/

Professional Summary

- 6+ years of experience in developing Client/Server and Web based applications using Microsoft Technologies .Net/.Net Core and SQL Server along with latest frontend technologies such as Angular 2/7
- Adept in C#, ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET Web API/Restful API, Ajax, Entity Framework, Umbraco CMS, jQuery,
 Typescript, JavaScript, Angular JS, Angular 2/7, Bootstrap/Foundation Framework, and SQL Server
- Experience in migration of legacy applications to enterprise technology and domain environments along with WCAG and OADA guidelines
- Flexible, enthusiastic and project-oriented team player with excellent written and leadership skills to develop creative solutions for challenging and evolving client needs

Technical Skills

Languages C#, ASP.NET, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, XML, SQL.

Databases Microsoft SQL Server (2014, 2012, 2008).

Frameworks .NET (4.7 – 4.0), ASP.NET, ASP.NET Web API, .NET Core, Entity Framework, Identity

Server, LINQ, Xamarin.

Web Technologies ASP.NET, ASP.NET MVC, .NET Core, Angular JS, Angular 2/7, Typescript, jQuery,

JavaScript, Ajax, Bootstrap/ Foundation, Kendo UI for Angular

Methodologies Agile (Scrum), OOD, Design patterns, Dependency Injection.

IDE/Tools/Applications Microsoft Visual Studio (2019, 2017, 2015, 2013, 2012), Microsoft SQL Server (2016,

2014, 2012, 2008), Microsoft TFS/DevOps, GIT, IIS Server.

Work Experience

Full Stack Developer/ Consultant

June 2018 - Present

Dapasoft Inc, Toronto, ON Visit: https://www.dapasoft.com/

- Enhanced the back-end REST API's using ASP.NET, C#, ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET Web API, .NET Core, Identity Server 4 & Microsoft SQL Server
- Overhauled the front-end user interfaces/user experience using HTML 5, CSS 3, Ajax, JSON, AngularJS/
 Angular 7, TypeScript, jQuery, JavaScript & Bootstrap
- Involvement of upgrading healthcare applications in Canada using Angular 7 and unit testing with Karma/Jasmine, .Net Core web API's and creating a core framework for fellow colleagues
- Implemented user-friendly UI's for desktops and handheld mobile devices for accessibility using bootstrap framework, responsive design and adhering to WCAG & OADA guidelines
- Improvement of website load times and user experience whilst also reducing of the overall file size by migrating to latest Angular framework
- Reduction of customer complaints by making the projects accessible by being WCAG and OADA compliant

Software Engineer

August 2014 – May 2018

H2Compute (Pvt) Ltd, Colombo, Sri Lanka

Visit: http://www.h2compute.com/en/

- Developed and maintained applications using ASP.NET, C#, ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET Web API, Entity
 Framework, Microsoft SQL Server, Team Foundation Server, LINQ, Umbraco Framework for back-end and
 Ajax, XML, JSON, AngularJS/Angular 2, jQuery, JavaScript, Bootstrap, HTML 5, CSS 3 for the front-end
- Implemented interactive & user-friendly UI's for desktops and handheld devices for mobile accessibility using bootstrap/foundation framework with web accessibility
- Developed & managed web applications mainly for European market
- Successfully deployed 5+ business web applications and directly collaborated with project managers, software
 architects and back-end developers in the process of front end, Web API and admin-portal/backend
 development
- Interacted & managed a team of 5 software engineers for the PHOV (e-Learning) Project, supported with day to day functional and technical knowledge

Associate Software Engineer

August 2013 – July 2014

Programus Ltd, Colombo, Sri Lanka Visit: http://www.programus.co.uk/

- Contributed as a junior developer in development of web applications using Microsoft ASP.NET framework (C#, MVC, MS SQL, LINQ)
- Used C#, Web API/web services and SQL to handle backend code, JSON/ JavaScript/ jQuery from the front end along with HTML 5 and CSS 3
- Participated in development of conversion of a desktop-based product suite to a web-based solution using bootstrap/foundation framework
- Developed mobile friendly/responsive web-based product portal with web accessibility

Education

Post Graduate Diploma in Information Systems Sri Lanka Institute of Information & Technology (SLIIT), Colombo, Sri Lanka	2015 – 2016
Bachelor of Information Technology University of Colombo, Colombo, Sri Lanka	2011 – 2015

Certifications and Training

Certified Associate in Project Management (CAPM) Project Management Institute, Certification ID: 2642937	2019 – Present
Microsoft Certified Professional, 70-480 Microsoft, Certification ID: F207-1834	2015 – Present